Clint McMahon

Minneapolis, MN | LinkedIn | Website | Github | 773-307-0422 | clintmcmahon@pm.me

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Principal engineer with extensive experience in software architecture, project leadership, and the development of complex data solutions within healthcare, legal, banking, government, and aviation sectors. Expert in designing architecture and systems that advance operational efficiency and user engagement. Proficient in .NET Core, React, JavaScript, SQL Server, and cloud technologies with a demonstrated ability to lead initiatives.

SKILLS

Front End: React, Angular 2+, JavaScript, TypeScript, GraphQL, OData, CSS, HTML

Back End: C#, .Net Core/8, WebAPI, REST, MVC, Python, OData

Database: SQL Server, MySQL, Postgres

Cloud/Dev Ops: Azure, B2C, AWS, Docker, Gitlab/Github CI/CD

Core Competencies: Technology Life Cycle Management, Strategic IT Planning & Execution, Software

Architecture & Cloud Solutions, Data Visualization & System Integration, Security & Compliance

WORK EXPERIENCE

Independent Consultant

Minneapolis, MN

Jan 2015-Present

Address a wide range of technical and business challenges for clients across industries. By leveraging cuttingedge technologies and innovative strategies to deliver sustainable, scalable solutions tailored to each client's unique needs.

Highlighted Projects & Clients

Hennepin Healthcare Research Institute

- Directed the strategic design and led the development of innovative web applications in .NET Core and React, addressing complex challenges through a domain-driven design approach, resulting in sustainable, scalable solutions.
- Lead technology consultant for the organization and related organizations (CDRG, SRTR). By leading the architecture, design, development and maintenance of critical web apps for use by doctors, researchers, patients, transplant centers and hospitals. Actively engaged in consultations with medical professionals and developers, ensuring alignment with technology strategies and best practices.
- Transformed organizational data handling and visualization needs into robust technical solutions using SQL Server, significantly enhancing strategic decision-making capabilities with a focus on domain-specific data modeling.
- Regularly interfaced with senior-level decision-makers on budgets, software capabilities, design principles, timelines, and development efforts, ensuring alignment with organizational goals and executive expectations using a domain-driven framework.
- Developed comprehensive project estimates and budget proposals for federal grant approvals, aligning financial forecasts with project scopes and regulatory requirements through a domain-centric evaluation.
- Led and mentored a team of developers, fostering skill development through regular code reviews and training sessions, and guided the creation of MVPs to streamline product launches and iterative improvements, all within a domain-driven design context.
- Implemented strategic data processes to enhance information flow and accuracy, significantly improving project outcomes and stakeholder satisfaction, guided by domain-driven principles.
- Technologies: .NET Core, C#, React, WebAPI HighCharts, GraphOL, SOL Server, AWS, CI/CD

JetTip Smart Flight Alerts

Led the development of the JetTip mobile app through creating a cross-platform iOS and Android app that delivers real-time flight alerts and aircraft tracking functionalities to aviation enthusiasts.

- Implemented advanced filtering and notification systems to enable users to receive personalized push notification alerts based on specific aircraft characteristics such as airline, aircraft type, and special livery, enhancing user engagement and application usability.
- Optimized app performance and user experience by integrating a fully configurable setup process that allows users to track desired flights within two minutes, incorporating seamless navigation and intuitive interface designs for optimal functionality.
- Led the development of a high-transactional .NET Core data processing solution, incorporating MySQL, Docker and Message Queues to manage real-time FAA flight data, significantly enhancing JetTip's smart alert system to process millions of records per day.
- Engineered the system for high scalability and rapid data processing using .NET Core, ensuring robust performance and optimizing system responsiveness to real-time changes in flight data.
- Implemented advanced data handling techniques in .NET Core and MySQL to ensure the integrity and speed of data transactions, enabling enhanced flight data products and services.
- Technologies: .NET Core, C#, React Native, WebAPI, OData, MySQL, Rabbit MQ, Docker

Cooley LLP

- Orchestrated the strategic planning and led the development of complex IT challenges, leveraging .NET and SOL Server to develop innovative, long-term solutions across the firm's legal practice, guided by domaindriven design principles.
- Mapped the firm's strategic business objectives to system design and implementation, enhancing data security and operational efficiency with Azure and SQL Server, while adhering to domain-driven design methodologies.
- Led and provided support for large-scale Azure deployment of API and Angular implementations and enterprise application migration to Azure AD and B2C authentication.
- Technologies: .NET Core, C#, Angular 2+, SQL Server, WebAPI OData, Azure, Azure B2C

Robins Kaplan LLP Minneapolis, MN Nov 2013 - Dec 2015

Sr. Engineer

Developed C# MVC application to give attorneys full text search capabilities of patent specific documents in PDF format. Empowering them to find the right results in less time and craft better arguments with less work.

Technologies: C#, MVC, JavaScript, jQuery, AWS, SQL Server, CSS

Wolters Kluwer New York, New York

Tech Lead

Feb 2011 - Nov 2013

- Tech lead in the development, architecture design and implementation of multi-language .Net applications utilizing SQL Server & Oracle backend databases, C# web parts and custom feature deployment.
- Managed hosting and application deployments to Azure cloud services.
- Technologies: C#, MVC, Azure, SQL Server, SharePoint, WCF

EDUCATION

Metropolitan State University BS MIS

St. Paul, MN